A Guide to the Papers of Robert Morton Hughes 1767-1959.
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- Pictorial Records
  - Photographs of R. M. Hughes (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Judge R. W. Hughes (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Val Verde (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of William and Mary (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Drawings of Ice House (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Sketches by Jas. Brown Hope (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Steel Engraving of Judge R. W. Hughes (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Steel Engraving of General Joseph E. Johnston (Used in his memoirs) 1874 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 18)
- Family Papers
  - General
    - Partial Hughes-Johnston-Preston Family Tree (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlet re: Johnston and Morton Families 1928 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Alumni List of Norfolk Academy: R. M. Hughes, Jr., Sidney Hughes (sons); Floyd Hughes (Nephew) listed 1927 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Judge R. W. Hughes (Father of R.M. Hughes)
    - General Correspondence 1849-1868 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence 1873-1879 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence 1880-1900 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Carrington Family Members 1843-1884 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with John M. Daniel 1853-1858 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Governor John B. Floyd 1851-1862 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Mrs. Eliza (R.W.) Hughes 1860-1869 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with J. P. Johnston 1840 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence with General Joseph E. Johnston 1865-1879 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with L. M. 1862-1864 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 14)
    - General Financial Correspondence 1860-1898 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Dispute with B. R. Johnston re: Mrs. Hughes' Inheritance 1845-1860 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Financial Dispute with W. W. Berkeley 1870-1885 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Financial Dealings with John Clarkson 1874-1876 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Financial Dealings with John W. Johnston 1879-1885 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Harmason Financial Matter (Old Debt) 1874-1896 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Financial Dealings with C. L. Perkins 1879-1883 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Bills from J. M. Roses and Sons 1889-1899 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with W. B. Moses and Sons re: Debts of Mrs. Van Vleck 1893-1895 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Promisory Notes 1898 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Property Tax Records 1869-1900 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Deeds re: Hughes' Real Estate 1871-1899 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Surveys, Maps of Hughes' Real Estate (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Announcements re: Hughes' Horses 1887-1894 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Appraisal of Hughes' Estate February 1902 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Records re: Hughes' estate 1901-1902 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Material re: Massie Trust Case 1852-1898 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Material re: J. T. L. Preston 1853-1855 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Material re: Thomas L. Preston 1851-1863 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Speech: "The Organic Law of England and the U.S." (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Speech: "Chief Justice Marshall and His Work" June 14, 1887 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Oath of Allegiance; Amnesty; Pardon 1865-1866 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 16)
    - General Political Correspondence 1868-1876 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 17)
    - General Political Correspondence 1877-1898 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence with William Mahone 1867-1876 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Recommendations of Hughes for U.S. Supreme Court Appointment 1877 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Hughes-Cameron Duel 1869 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Dispute with Roger Pryor 1856 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: Attack from Col. Ruffin 1884-1885 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence re: Virginia and Kentucky Railroad 1858-1867 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence re: Governor John B. Floyd 1861-1888 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Peter J. Otey re: Governor Floyd (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Draft Biography of Governor John B. Floyd (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Copies of Letters re: Floyd Resignation as Secretary of War 1860 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Receipt in Patrick Henry's Handwriting (According to R. W. Hughes) 1767 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Eliza Johnston Hughes
    - General Correspondence 1846-1901 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Governor John B. Floyd 1839-1860 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Mrs. Sally B. Floyd (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with John Preston Johnston 1839 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with John Preston Johnston 1840 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with John Preston Johnston 1841 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with John Preston Johnston 1842 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with John Preston Johnston 1843 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with John Preston Johnston 1844 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with John Preston Johnston 1845 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with John Preston Johnston 1846-47 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence with Beverly R. Johnston 1843-1848 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Joseph E. Johnston 1848-1887 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Financial Records 1903-1905 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Real Estate Deeds 1903-1905 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Charles C. Johnston
    - Correspondence 1824-1831 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Eliza Preston Johnston
    - Correspondence 1821-1827 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Governor John Floyd
    - Letter to Governor of New York re: Fugitive Slaves 1832 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 7)
  - John B. Floyd
    - General Pre-Civil War Correspondence 1831-1861 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Mrs. Sally B. Preston Floyd 1855-1862 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Diary 1838-1845 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with John Tyler 1843-1860 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence re: Governors of Virginia 1848-1849 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Governor's Message December 3, 1849 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence while Secretary of War 1857-1860 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Material re: Fort Snelling Dispute 1857 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Material re: Acceptances Controversy 1860-1861 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Letters from General Floyd 1861 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Letters from General Floyd 1861-1862 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Letters to General Floyd 1861 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Letters to General Floyd 1862-1863 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with General Henry A. Wise 1861 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Orders; Commissions; Rosters 1861-1862 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Morning Reports 1861-1862 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Diary of an Officer in Floyd's Command 1862 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Civil War Correspondence 1861-1862 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Items in Floyd's Handwriting (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Sally B. Preston Floyd
    - Correspondence 1839-1879 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Edward Johnston
    - Edward Johnston-John W. Correspondence 1847-1848 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 10)
  - John Preston Johnson
    - Correspondence 1837-1839 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence 1840-1845 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 12)
  - General Joseph E. Johnston
    - Correspondence with Various Johnston Relatives 1839-1861 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with Beverly R. Johnston 1847-1868 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Draft of Letter to Jefferson Davis Protesting Ranking in Confederate Army 1861 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Letter from Wade Hampton January 13, 1863 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 16)
    - General Correspondence 1861-1865 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Copy of Convention signed with General Sherman April 27, 1865 (Box-folder Box 26, Folder 18)
    - General Correspondence 1861-1878 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence 1880-1886 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence 1886-1890 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Letters from General James Longstreet 1877-1890 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Letter from General Jubal A. Early February 4, 1875 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Clarence Buel (Century Magazine) 1884-1888 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Robert V. Johnson (Century Magazine) 1884-1888 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with North American Review 1886-1887 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Letters to General Valencia (Mexican War Souvenirs) 1836-1837 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Bennett Place Memorial Correspondence 1923-1924 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Bennett Place Memorial Assocation Legislative Enactment 1923 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Bennett Place Memorial Inscription (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Bennett Place Memorial, Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Bennett Place Memorial Unveiling - Address by General Julian S. Carr November 8, 1923 (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 14)
    - "Some Reminiscences of Joseph E. Johnston" by Robert M. Hughes (Box-folder Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Rough Draft of Johnston's Memoirs - Introductory Section (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Rough Draft of Johnston's Memoirs - Introductory Section (different version) (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Rough Draft of Johnston's Memoirs - Introductory Section (third version) (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Rough Draft of Johnston's Memoirs - Miscellaneous Pages from First Part (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 4)
    - General Comments about the Confederacy (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Material re: Northern Virginia Campaign (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Accounts of Battles with Sherman in Georgia, 2 folders (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 7-8)
    - Account of Final Battles (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Material re: Last Days of War (Box-folder Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Draft of Defense Against Critical Articles (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Defense of Actions During Early Command in Virginia (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Material for Defense Against Accusations by Jefferson Davis (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Defense Against Charges by General Beauregard re: Manassas Campaign (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Various Correspondents
    - John Preston Correspondence (R.M.Hughes' Maternal Great Grandfather) 1796 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 5)
    - John Preston-Francis Preston Correspondence 1787-1821 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Sarah Campbell Preston Correspondence and Will 1816-1847 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Lettitia Floyd Letter to Benjamin Rush Floyd February 28, 1843 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Thomas P. McDowell Real Estate Deeds (Preston Family) 1857-1858 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 9)
    - William Radford Correspondence 1830-1850 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Robert M. Hughes, Jr.
    - Correspondence 1921-1940 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence 1941-1950 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 12)
    - "The Tidewater Trail" Magazine October-November 1944 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Publications Collected by R. M. Hughes, Jr. 1941-1946 (Box-folder Box 29, Folder 14)
- Historical Studies
  - Governor John B. Floyd
    - Floyd's Role in Medal for General Winfield Scott 1848 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Material re: Acceptances Controversy in War Department 1858-1861 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Letters re: Floyd's Resignation as Secretary of War December, 1860 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Material Re: Floyd's Views During Secession Crisis 1860-1861 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Letters from Winfield Scott and James Buchanan to the National Intelligencer 1862 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Copies of Correspondence from General Robert E. Lee 1861 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Confederate Military Orders 1862 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Biographical Sketch of General Floyd (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Material Re: Floyd (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Hughes' Correspondence Re: Floyd 1888-1920 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Hughes' Correspondence Re: Floyd 1921-1925 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Hughes' Correspondence Re: Floyd 1926-1930 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Hughes' Correspondence Re: Floyd 1931-1937 (Box-folder Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with Scribner's re: James Truslow Adams' Textbook 1935-1936 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with George F. Milton 1931-1937 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence re: Harper's Article on Floyd's Role at Ft. Donelson 1911 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence re: Harper's Article on Floyd's Role at Ft. Donelson 1912 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: R. M. H. Article in Tyler's Quarterly 1923 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence re: Articles by Philip Auchenpaugh in Tyler's Quarterly 1923-1930 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Confederate Veteran Magazine 1928-1931 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Issues of Confederate Veteran with Articles on Floyd 1929-1931 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Hughes' Response to Mark Twain Criticism of Floyd from Virginia Magazine of History and Biography 1930-1931 (Box-folder Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence re: Hughes' Article in Virginia Historical Magazine 1935 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence re: Hughes' Article in Virginia Historical Magazine 1936-1937 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with S. F. Hurt re: Floyd Family 1938 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 3)
  - General Joseph E. Johnston
    - Copies of Letters from Robert E. Lee 1839-1861 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Copies of Letters to Johnston During the Civil War 1861-1865 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Copies of Letters from Wade Hampton 1863 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence re: Louis Wigfall Letter to J.E.J. dated 1874 1934-1935 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Source Material re: Johnston's Campaigns 1861-1874 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Charleston Daily Courier, Nashville Dispatch Reports of Atlantic Campaign September 26-October 12, 1864 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper: Jefferson Davis Speech in Macon, Georgia November 5, 1864 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Baltimore Sun Article re: Convention J.E.J. Signed with General Sherman in 1865 February 14, 1886 (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Battle Maps, Army of the Cumberland 1875, 2 folders (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 12-13)
    - Maps of Atlanta Campaign (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Material re: J.E.J. (Box-folder Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence with Appleton Co. re: First Edition of J.E.J. Biography 1891-1925 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with James Wilson (Appleton) re: J.E.J. Biography 1891-1896 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Appleton Co. re: Royalties from J.E.J. Biography 1894-1923, 2 folders (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 3-4)
    - General Correspondence re: New Edition of J.E.J. Biography 1937 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Library of Congress re: Copyright to J.E.J. Biography 1937 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Donald Bartlett re: New Edition of J.E.J. Biography 1938-1939 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Articles on Johnston 1912-1926 (Box-folder Box 33, Folder 8)
    - General Correspondence re: Joseph E. Johnston 1891-1899 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence re: Joseph E. Johnston 1900-1919 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence re: Joseph E. Johnston 1920-1929 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence re: Joseph E. Johnston 1930-1939 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with War Office 1891-1894 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Joseph Brown (Civil War Governor of Georgia) 1889-1898 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Robert E. Lee Camp 1894-1908 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Military Service Institution 1912 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Gamaliel Bradford 1912 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Gamaliel Bradford 1912-1925 (Box-folder Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with C. I. Millard re: J.E.J. and other Civil War Topics 1912-1933 (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with T. R. Hay 1920-1924 (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with T. R. Hay 1925-1929 (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with North Carolina Historical Commission 1922-1933 (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with American Historical Review Re: William Dodd's Comments on J.E.J. 1924 (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Material re: Paper by A. P. James on J. E. J. at A. H. A. Convention 1925 (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Material Re: Confederate Monument at Stone Mountain, Georgia 1925-1926 (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Century Magazine re: Article by William Dodd 1927 (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Douglass Southall Freeman 1927-1935 (Box-folder Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Landon C. Bell re: J.E.J. and Related Topics 1929-1930 (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Dispute over Longwood Marker 1930-1934 (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Dispute over Longwood Marker 1935 (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Col. D. B. Sanger Re: Biography of J.E.J. 1935-1937 (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: Portrait of J.E.J. at Farmville State Teachers College 1936-1938 (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with George F. Milton (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence re: Proposed Portrait of J.E.J. 1938 (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Civil War Topics
    - Flags of the Confederate States of America 1907 (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with General F. Maurice 1925-1927 (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 9)
    - "'Civil War' or 'War Between the States'" Hughes Article in William and Mary Quarterly January, 1925 (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence re Article "'Civil War' or 'War Between the States'" 1934-1936 (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Monitor vs. Merrimac (Virginia) (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Location of the Wreck of the Cumberland (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Confederate and Federal Constitutions Compared (Box-folder Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Secession Ordinances & Documents (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Lee and Secession (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Clippings re: Muzzey's History Text 1930 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence re: Muzzey's History Text 1930 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: Muzzey's History Text 1931 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence re: Muzzey's History Text 1932 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence re: Muzzey's History Text 1933 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence re: Muzzey's History Text 1934 (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Review of Muzzey's "History of the American People" (Box-folder Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Virginia History
    - "The Birth of America" A Play by Matthew Page Andrews 1920 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk Bicentennial Material 1936 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Response to Harold U. Faulkner's Article on Colonial History in Harper's 1925-1926 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Williamsburg Material 1933 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Religious Toleration in Virginia 1926-1938 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Letter from Edmund Randolph to St. George Tucker May 7, 1780 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 6)
    - "The Jamestown Exposition" (booklet) 1907 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Yorktown Sesquicentennial 1931 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Proclamation of New Seal of Virginia December 2, 1931 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook on Virginia Landmarks (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Cape Henry Landing 1925-1936 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Flag Flown at Landing of First Colonists 1931-1935 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Hughes Paper Comparing Jamestown and Plymouth Settlements (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Celebration of Tercentenary of Jamestown and Plymouth (program) 1920 (Box-folder Box 38, Folder 14)
  - General
    - General Correspondence on Historical Topics 1890-1905 (Box-folder Box 39, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence on Historical Topics 1920-1939 (Box-folder Box 39, Folder 2)
    - George Sheffield's Index to Ecclectic Magazine, Vols. 1-50 1844-1859 (Box-folder Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings on Historical Topics 1924 (Box-folder Box 39, Folder 4)
- Index Cards
  - Index Cards for Letters at one time in Hughes' Possession (Box 40)
- Miscellaneous
  - Proceedings of the Research Club 1914 (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of the Research Club 1915 (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Proceedings of the Research Club 1916 (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Proceedings of the Research Club 1917 (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Proceedings of the Research Club 1920 (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence re: Bond Issue for Roads 1919 (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Clippings re: Bond Issue for Roads 1919 (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Writings, Articles re: Bond Issue for Roads 1919-1923 (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Poetry Society of Virginia (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Virginia State Seal & Flag (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Norfolk Law Library (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Method of Electing Vice Presidents (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Books & Journals - Purchasing & Collecting (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Material re: Missing Issues of Southern Literary Messenger (Box-folder Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Dried Floral Arrangement (Box-folder Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Jamestown Exposition - Accounting of Expenses (Box-folder Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Sketches of Historic Sites and Famous Americans (Box-folder Box 42, Folder 3)
  - "Sixty Years Ago" Address given by R. M. Hughes June 12, 1933 (Box-folder Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Rough Draft of "Annals and Reminiscences of an Octogenarian" (Box-folder Box 42, Folder 5)
  - "Annals and Reminiscences of an Octogenarian" (Box-folder Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook 1872 (Box-folder Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook August 21, 1873 (Box-folder Box 42, Folder 8)
- Oversized Materials
  - Certificate of Appointment as U.S. Attorney for the Western District of Virginia February 6, 1871 (Box Oversize Box 1)